German Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
German Painting Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 21
Yale University Arts Library
27.5
66 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of German paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by individual artist name. The individual artist material is further divided primarily by location of work. The individual artist portion is preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of German paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Painting, German; Photographs; Reproductions
- Anonymous.
  - XII Century., 1 (Box 1)
  - XIII Century., 4 (Box 1)
  - XIV Century, 55
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - General works., 25 (Box 1)
    - Master Bertram of Mindin., 5 (Box 1)
    - Master of the Klosterneuberg Altar., 5 (Box 1)
    - Master of St. Veronica., 11 (Box 1)
    - Master of Wittingau., 4 (Box 1)
      Master William see: Master of St.Veronica.
    - Prague School., 5 (Box 1)
  - XV Century., 299
    - General drawings., 12 (Box 2)
    - General paintings., 39 (Box 2)
    - Bavarian School., 4 (Box 3)
    - Bohemian School, 3 (Box 3)
    - Cologne School., 11 (Box 3)
    - Middle Rhenish School., 6 (Box 3)
    - Swabian School., 12 (Box 3)
    - Swiss School., 4 (Box 3)
    - Upper Rhenish School, 7 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Masters., 81 (Box 4)
    - Master of the Bartholomew Altar., 23 (Box 5)
    - Master of the Darmstadt Passion., 8 (Box 5)
    - Master Francke., 19 (Box 5)
    - Hausbuch Master., 13 (Box 5)
    - Master of Heiligenkreuz., 10 (Box 6)
    - Master of the Life of Mary., 23 (Box 6)
    - Master of Liesborn., 6 (Box 6)
      - [unittitle added: see error report]
    - Master of Little Paradise Garden., 6 (Box 6)
    - Master of the Sterzinger Altar., 8 (Box 6)
    - Master of the Tegernsee Tabula Magna., 4 (Box 6)
  - XVI Century., 73
    - General drawings., 9 (Box 7)
    - General paintings., 30 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous masters., 22 (Box 7)
      - Unknown masters., 2 (Box 7)
      - Master A. G. of 1540., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master A. S., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master H. F., 2 (Box 7)
      - Master H. P. (H. Pruckendorfer?), 1 (Box 7)
      - Master M.. Z., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master N. K., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of St. Severin., 2 (Box 7)
      - Master of Saxony, 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Angrer Portraits., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Miracle of Mariazell, 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Muehldorf Altar., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Oberaltaich Man of Sorrows., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Parrot., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Petrarch Illustrations., 2 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Rottal Epitaph., 1 (Box 7)
      - Master of the Seitenstetten Mater Dolorosa., 1 (Box 7)
      - Schwabian Master., 1 (Box 7)
    - Master of Messkirch., 8 (Box 7)
    - Master of Pulkau, 4 (Box 7)
      Also known as Master of the Historia.
      For sculpture on the Pulkau Altar see: Sculpture, Germany, XVI Century.
  - XVII Century., 1 (Box 7)
  - XVIII Century., 4 (Box 7)
  - XIX-XX Century., 3 (Box 7)
    Includes a file of miscellaneous clippings.
- A
  - Miscellaneous Artists A., 17
    Includes a file of miscellaneous clippings of various "A" artists.
    - Abel, Josef, 1764-1818., 1 (Box 8)
    - Achenbach, Oswald, 1827-1905.., 1 (Box 8)
    - Ackermann, Max, 1887-1975., 2 (Box 8)
    - Adam, Albrecht, 1786-1862., 4 (Box 8)
  - Individual Artists A., 154
    - Aachen, Hans von, 1552-1615, 8 (Box 8)
    - Achenbach, Andreas, 1815-1905, 9 (Box 8)
    - Aldegrever, Heinrich, 1502-1558 (?), 5 (Box 8)
    - Altdorfer, Albrecht, 1480-1538., 103
      - Drawings., 29 (Box 8)
      - Paintings., 74 (Box 9)
      - Workshop of Altdorfer., 7 (Box 10)
    - Amberger, Christoph, c.1500-1562/3, 9 (Box 10)
    - Apt, Ulrich, the Elder, 1455-1532., 5 (Box 10)
    - Asam, Cosmas and Egid (brothers), 1686-1739, 1686-1739., 8 (Box 10)
      - Asam Brothers., 1 (Box 10)
      - Asam, Cosmas-Damien., 4 (Box 10)
      - Asam, Egid Quirin., 3 (Box 10)
- B
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for Artists "B".
  - Miscellaneous Artists, "B", 59 (Box 10)
    - Baader, Johannes, 1876-1955., 3 (Box 10)
    - Baargeld, Alfred Grunewald, 1891-1927., 2 (Box 10)
    - Bachem, Bele, 1916-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Barlach, Ernst, 1870- 1938., 2 (Box 10)
    - Bauer, Conrad, active 1530., 1 (Box 10)
    - Baum, Paul, 1858-1932., 4 (Box 10)
    - Beck, Leonard, c.1480-1452., 3 (Box 10)
    - Becker, Carl, 1820-1900., 1 (Box 10)
    - Begas, Adalbert Franz Eugen, 1836-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Beham, Barthel, 1502-1540., 2 (Box 10)
    - Beham, Hans Sebald, 1500-1550., 4 (Box 10)
    - Bemelmans, Ludwig, 1898-1962., 1 (Box 10)
    - Berentz, Christian, 1658-1722., 2 (Box 10)
    - Bergmann-Michel, Ella, 1896-., 2 (Box 10)
    - Bismarck, Jack von Reppert, 1861-., 2 (Box 10)
    - Bissier, Julius Heinrich, 1893-1965., 4 (Box 10)
    - Bitlor, Grin, c.1480., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bocklin, Arnold, 1827-1901., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bockstiegel, Peter August, 1889-1951., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bohmer, Gunter, 1912-1986., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bornemann, Hans, c.1444-1447., 1 (Box 10)
    - Brand, Johann Christian, 1722-1795., 1 (Box 10)
    - Brandel, Fritz, XIX Century., 1 (Box 10)
    - Brauer, Erich, 1929-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Breinlinger, Hans, 1888-1963., 1 (Box 10)
    - Brinckmann, Philip H., XVIII Century., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bruckner, Gerhard, XX Century., 1 (Box 10)
    - Bruhlmann, Hans, 1878-1911., 2 (Box 10)
    - Brunswick monogrammist, active 1525-1550., 1 (Box 10)
    - Buchheim, Lothar-Gunther, 1918-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Buchheister, Carl, 1890-1964., 4 (Box 10)
    - Buchholz, Erich, 1891-1972., 1 (Box 10)
    - Buchholz, Karl, 1849-1889., 1 (Box 10)
    - Buchser, Frank, 1828-1890., 1 (Box 10)
    - Busch, Wilhelm, 1832-1908., 1 (Box 10)
    - Buttersack, Bernhard, 1858-1899., 1 (Box 10)
  - Individual Artists B, 342
    - Baegert, Derick, 1440-1515., 6 (Box 11)
    - Baldung Grien, Hans, 1480-1545., 85 (Box 11)
      - Drawings., 18 (Box 11)
      - Paintings., 67 (Box 11)
    - Baselitz, Georg, 1938-., 13 (Box 12)
    - Bauer, Rudolph, 1889-., 26 (Box 12)
    - Baumeister, Willi, 1889-1955., 13 (Box 12)
      Includes of folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Beckmann, Max, 1884-1950., 61 (Box 13)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 13)
      - Paintings., 57 (Box 13)
        - General subjects., 44 (Box 13)
        - Self-portraits., 13 (Box 13)
    - Bellmer, Hans, 1902-1975., 7 (Box 13)
      Includes a large folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Blechen, Karl, 1798-1840., 7 (Box 14)
    - Bocklin, Arnold, 1827-1901., 44 (Box 14)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 14)
      - Paintings., 40 (Box 14)
    - Bracht, Eugen, 1857-., 7 (Box 14)
    - Breu, Jorg, 1480-1537., 14 (Box 14)
    - Bromberger, Dora, 1885-1942., 7 (Box 15)
    - Bruyn, Bartholomaus, 1493-1555., 21 (Box 15)
    - Burkel, Heinrich, 1802-1869., 7 (Box 15)
    - Burkmair, Hans, 1473-1531., 24 (Box 15)
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 15)
      - Paintings., 18 (Box 15)
- C
  - Miscellaneous Artists C, 21 (Box 16)
    - Caldenbach, Martin, 1480-1518., 4 (Box 16)
    - Camphausen, W., 1818-1885., 1 (Box 16)
    - Candid, Pieter (de Witte), 1548-1628., 1 (Box 16)
    - Carus, Carl Gustave, 1789-1869., 6 (Box 16)
    - Caspar, Karl, 1879-1956., 1 (Box 16)
    - Catel, Franz Ludwig, 1778-1856., 4 (Box 16)
    - Cermak, Jaroslav, 1831-1878., 1 (Box 16)
    - Claudius, Wilhelm, 1854-., 1 (Box 16)
    - Closterman, Johann B., 1650-1711., 1 (Box 16)
    - Cramer, Konrad, 1888-1960., 1 (Box 16)
  - Individual Artists C, 304
    - Campendonk, Heinrich, 1889-1957., 14 (Box 16)
    - Chodowiecki, Daniel, 1726-1801., 7 (Box 16)
    - Corinth, Lovis, 1858-1925., 35 (Box 16)
    - Cornelius, Peter von, 1783-1867., 8 (Box 17)
    - Cranach, Lucas the Elder, 1472-1553, 214
      Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Drawings., 11 (Box 17)
      - Paintings., 203
        - Miscellaneous collections., 25 (Box 17)
        - Private collections., 22 (Box 17)
        - Miscellaneous cities A-F., 18 (Box 18)
        - Miscellaneous cities G-N., 18 (Box 18)
        - Miscellaneous cities O-Z., 16 (Box 18)
        - Aschaffenburg., 9 (Box 19)
        - Berlin., 21 (Box 19)
        - Chicago., 5 (Box 19)
        - Dresden., 23 (Box 19)
        - Munich., 10 (Box 19)
        - New York., 10 (Box 20)
        - Paris., 6 (Box 20)
        - Vienna., 15 (Box 20)
        - Washington., 5 (Box 20)
    - Cranach, Lucas the Younger, 1515-1586., 9 (Box 20)
    - School of Lucas Cranach., 17 (Box 20)
- D
  - Miscellaneous Artists D., 21 (Box 21)
    - Dahm, Helen, 1878-1968., 1 (Box 21)
    - Danhauser, Josef, 1805-1845., 1 (Box 21)
    - Desmarees, George, 1697-1776., 2 (Box 21)
    - Dietrich, C.W., 1712-1774., 1 (Box 21)
    - Dill, Ludwig, 1848-., 1 (Box 21)
    - Dillis, Johan Georg von, 1759-1841., 3 (Box 21)
    - Dokoupil, Jiri Georg, 1954-., 2 (Box 21)
    - Dorffest, ?, XX Century., 1 (Box 21)
    - Dorner, Johann Jacob the Younger, 1775-1852, 1 (Box 21)
    - Drewes, Werner, 1899-., 4 (Box 21)
    - Drexel, Walter, 1890-., 1 (Box 21)
    - Ducker, Eugene G., 1841-, 1 (Box 21)
    - Dzubas, Friedebald, 1915-., 2 (Box 21)
  - Individual Artists D, ? photographs
    - Denner, Balthasar, 1685-1749., 8 (Box 21)
    - Deutsch, M. (Box 21)
      See: Manuel, N.
    - Dix, Otto, 1891-1969., 29 (Box 21)
      Includes folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Durer, Albrecht, 1471-1528., 361
      - Drawings., 173
        - Various locations.
          - Miscellaneous drawings., 14 (Box 21)
          - Figures and nudes., 10 (Box 22)
          - Heads and portraits., 16 (Box 22)
          - Landscapes, plants and animals., 18 (Box 22)
          - Life of Christ (scenes)., 12 (Box 22)
        - Basel., 5 (Box 23)
        - Berlin., 20 (Box 23)
        - Bremen., 7 (Box 23)
        - Florence., 5 (Box 23)
        - London., 8 (Box 23)
        - Paris., 7 (Box 23)
        - Vienna., 51 (Box 24)
          - Figures and portraits., 19 (Box 24)
          - Landscapes, plants and animals., 17 (Box 24)
          - Life of Christ (scenes)., 15 (Box 24)
      - Paintings., 188
        - Various locations., 37 (Box 25)
          - Portraits., 20 (Box 25)
          - Religious subjects., 17 (Box 25)
        - Berlin., 16 (Box 25)
        - Dresden., 19 (Box 26)
        - Florence., 15 (Box 26)
        - Madrid., 11 (Box 26)
        - Munich., 18 (Box 26)
        - Nuremburg., 8 (Box 26)
        - Prague., 7 (Box 27)
        - Vienna., 51 (Box 27)
          - General subjects., 8 (Box 27)
          - Four apostles., 13 (Box 27)
          - Paumgartner Altarpiece., 9 (Box 27)
          - Religious scenes., 21 (Box 27)
        - Washington., 6 (Box 27)
- E
  - Miscellaneous Artists E, 10 (Box 28)
    - Ebers, Hermann, 1881-1955., 1 (Box 28)
    - Edlinger, Johann Georg, 1741-1819., 1 (Box 28)
    - Egger-Linz, A., 1868-1926., 2 (Box 28)
    - Ende, Edgar, 1901-1965., 1 (Box 28)
    - Engert, Erasmus, 1796-1871., 1 (Box 28)
    - Entwicklung, Elsa F., (dates?), 1 (Box 28)
    - Erbsloh, Adolf, 1881-1947, 3 (Box 28)
  - Individual Artists E., 109
    - Edzard, Dietz, 1893- 1963., 5 (Box 28)
    - Elsheimer, Adam, 1578-1610, 22 (Box 28)
      See also: Painting, Italy, Saraceni, Carlo.
    - Engel, Otto, 1866-1949., 8 (Box 28)
    - Ernst, Max, 1891-1976., 74 (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 25 (Box 29)
      - New York., 38 (Box 29)
      - Private collections., 11 (Box 29)
- F
  - Miscellaneous Artists F, 34 (Box 30)
    - Faber von Creuznach, Conrad, 1500-1552., 6 (Box 30)
    - Faistenburger, Anton, 1663-1708., 1; paintings (Box 30)
    - Felixmuller, Conrad, 1897-1977., 4 (Box 30)
    - Ferdinand, Johann Heinrich, 1785-1841., 1 (Box 30)
    - Feselen, Melchior, active 1521-1538., 3 (Box 30)
    - Fetting, Renier, 1949-., 2 (Box 30)
    - Fischinger, Oskar, 1900-1967., 1 (Box 30)
    - Flegel, Georg, 1563-1638., 4 (Box 30)
    - Flickel, Paul, 1852-1903., 1 (Box 30)
    - Fohr, Karl Phillip, 1795-1818., 3 (Box 30)
    - Fries, Ernst, 1801-1833., 1 (Box 30)
    - Fuger, Freidrich Heinrich, 1751-1818., 2 (Box 30)
      Artist's name also spelled "Fueger"
    - Funhof, Hinrik, active 1475-1485., 2 (Box 30)
    - Funk, Hans, 1470-1539., 1 (Box 30)
    - Furtnagel, Lucas, 1505- after 1546., 2 (Box 30)
  - Individual Artists F., 171
    - Feuerbach, Anselm, 1829-1850., 29 (Box 30)
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 30)
      - Paintings., 24 (Box 30)
    - Fischer, Oskar, 1892-., 11 (Box 31)
    - Friedrich, Caspar David, 1774-1840., 106
      - Location unlisted.., 7 (Box 31)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 29 (Box 31)
      - 29 photographs. (Box 31)
      - Cologne., 9 (Box 32)
      - Essen., 6 (Box 32)
      - Hamburg., 13 (Box 32)
      - Hanover., 6 (Box 32)
      - Winterthur., 7 (Box 32)
    - Fries, Hans, c.1465-1518., 16 (Box 32)
    - Frueauf, Rueland, 1440-1507., 9 (Box 32)
- G
  - Miscellaneous Artists G, 31 (Box 33)
    - Geerten Tot St, Jans, active 1465-1493., 1 (Box 33)
    - Geiger, Carl A., XX Century?, 1 (Box 33)
    - Gerhard, Hubert, 1540-1620., 1 (Box 33)
    - Gertner, Peter, active 1527., 1 (Box 33)
    - Giltinger, Gumpolt, 1481-1547., 1 (Box 33)
    - Glehn, Wilfred G. von, 1870-, 3 (Box 33)
    - Gleichen-Russwurm, Ferdinand-Ludwig, 1836-1901., 1 (Box 33)
    - Goldschmidt, Hilde, 1897-., 1 (Box 33)
    - Goller, Bruno, 1901-., 1 (Box 33)
    - Gortschacher, Urban, XVI Century., 1 (Box 33)
    - Gotsch, Friedrich Karl, 1900-1984., 3 (Box 33)
    - Goz, Gottfried Bernhard, 1708-1774., 2 (Box 33)
      Artist's name also spelled "Gotz."
    - Graubner, Gotthard, 1930-., 1 (Box 33)
    - Grun, Jules, 1868-., 4 (Box 33)
    - Grutzner, Eduard, 1846-1925., 1 (Box 33)
    - Gunschmann, Carl, 1895-., 1 (Box 33)
    - Gunther, Ignaz, 1725-1775., 3 (Box 33)
    - Gunther, Matthaus, 1705-1788/91., 1 (Box 33)
    - Guylenborch, ??, 1 (Box 33)
    - Gysbrechts, late XVII Century, 2 (Box 33)
  - Individual Artists G, 161
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832., 5 (Box 33)
    - Graf, Urs, 1485-1527/8., 23 (Box 33)
    - Graff, Anton, 1736-1813., 10 (Box 33)
    - Grosz, George, 1893-1959., 44 (Box 34)
      - Drawings., 13 (Box 34)
      - Paintings., 31; paintings (Box 34)
    - Grunewald, Matthias, 1475-1528., 79
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 34)
      - Paintings., 73
        - Miscellaneous cities., 14 (Box 34)
        - Colmar., 49 (Box 35)
          - Eisenheim Altarpiece, closed., 16 (Box 35)
          - Eisenheim Altarpiece, first opening., 24 (Box 35)
          - Eisenheim Altarpiece, second opening., 9 (Box 35)
        - Munich., 6 (Box 35)
        - Washington., 4 (Box 35)
- H
  - Miscellaneous Artists H., 49 (Box 36)
    - Hagemeister, Karl, 1848-1933., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hans von Tuebingen, 1400-1462., 2 (Box 36)
    - Hartig, Hans, XX Century., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hauber, Joseph, 1766-1834., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hauptmann, Ivo, 1886-1973, 2 (Box 36)
    - Haussmann, Elias Gottlieb, 1695-1774., 1 (Box 36)
    - Heintz, Joseph the Elder, 1564-1609., 1 (Box 36)
    - Heintz, Joseph the Younger, 1600-1678., 3; paintings (Box 36)
      Artist's name also spelled "Heinz."
    - Henseler, Ernest, 1852-1900., 1; paintings (Box 36)
    - Herbig, Otto, 1889-1971., 1 (Box 36)
    - Herlin, Friedrich, active 1459-1500., 3 (Box 36)
    - Herrant, Crispin, -1549., 1 (Box 36)
    - Herrmann, Curt, 1854-1929., 3 (Box 36)
    - Hess, Peter von, 1792-1871., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hesse, Hans, active 1497-1521., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hetsch, Philipp Friedrich, 1758-1838., 2 (Box 36)
    - Hildebrandt, Ferdinand Theodore, 1804-1874., 2 (Box 36)
    - Hilderbrandt, Lily, 1887-1974., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hinz, Johann Georg, 1662-1700., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hoch, Hannah, 1889-1978., 6 (Box 36)
    - Hodicke, Karl, 1938-., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hoerle, Angelika, 1899-1923., 3 (Box 36)
    - Hoff, Karl, 1838-1890., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hoffman, Johan, 1824-1895., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hoffmann, Hans, 1545-1591., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hoffmann-Fallersleben, Franz, 1855-., 1 (Box 36)
    - Holzel, Adolf, 1853-1934., 1 (Box 36)
    - Holzer, Johann Evangelist, 1709-1740., 1 (Box 36)
    - Hopfer, Daniel, active 1493-1536., 2 (Box 36)
    - Hurdeberg, Jurgen von, XX Century., 1 (Box 36)
    - Huth, W.R., XX Century., 1 (Box 36)
  - Individual Artists H, 440
    - Hackert, Philipp, 1737-1807., 5 (Box 36)
    - Hartung, Hans, 1904-1989., 10 (Box 36)
    - Hasenclever, Johann Peter, 1810-1853., 7 (Box 37)
    - Heartfield, John, 1891-1968., 6 (Box 37)
    - Heckel, Erich, 1883-1970., 24 (Box 37)
    - Hirschvogel, Augustin, 1503-1553., 6 (Box 37)
    - Hitler, Adolf, 1890-1945., 2 (Box 37)
      Includes a folder with miscellaneous clippings.
    - Hofer, Karl, 1878-1955., 22 (Box 37)
    - Holbein, Ambrosius, 1494-1521., 10 (Box 37)
    - Holbein, Hans, the Elder, 1460/70-1524., 32 (Box 38)
      - Drawings., 7 (Box 38)
      - Paintings., 25 (Box 38)
    - Holbein, Hans, the Younger, 1497-1543, 257
      - Drawings., 96
        - Miscellaneous locations., 35 (Box 38)
          - General drawings., 11 (Box 38)
          - Portraits, Male., 16 (Box 38)
          - Portraits, Female., 8 (Box 38)
        - Basel., 10; drawings. (Box 39)
        - Windsor Castle., 51 (Box 39)
          - Portraits, Female., 20 (Box 39)
          - Portraits, Male., 31 (Box 39)
      - Paintings., 161
        - Miscellaneous cities., 45 (Box 40)
        - Basel., 23 (Box 40)
        - Berlin., 7 (Box 41)
        - Darmstadt., 3 (Box 41)
        - Dresden., 8 (Box 41)
        - Florence., 4 (Box 41)
        - London., 27 (Box 41)
        - New York., 17 (Box 42)
        - Paris., 9 (Box 42)
        - Rome., 4 (Box 42)
        - Vienna., 3 (Box 42)
        - Washington., 7 (Box 42)
        - Windsor Castle., 4 (Box 42)
    - Hollar, Wenceslaus, 1607-1677, 5 (Box 42)
    - Huber, Wolf, 1490-1553., 49 (Box 43)
      - Drawings., 36 (Box 43)
      - Paintings., 13 (Box 43)
    - Hundertwasser, Friedrich, 1928-., 5 (Box 43)
- I
  - Miscellaneous Artists I, 6 (Box 44)
    - Immendorf, Jorg, 1945-., 3 (Box 44)
    - Isenmann, Casper, active 1435-1472., 3 (Box 44)
  - Individual Artists I. (Box 44)
- J
  - Miscellaneous Artists J, 5 (Box 44)
    - Jacobi, Rudolf, 1889-., 2 (Box 44)
    - Jettmar, Rudolf, 1869-1939., 2 (Box 44)
    - Juvenel, Paul, 1574-1643., 1 (Box 44)
  - Individual Artists J, 44 (Box 44)
    - Jawlensky, Alexej von, 1867-1941., 44 (Box 44)
- K
  - Miscellaneous Artists K., 49 (Box 45)
    - Kaaz, Karl Ludwig, 1776-1810, 1 (Box 45)
    - Kaiser, Ernst, 1803-1865., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kallmorgen, Friedrich, 1856-1924., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kampf, Arthur, 1864-1950., 1 (Box 45)
    - Katzheimer, Lorenz, active 1480-1505., 1 (Box 45)
    - Katzheimer, Wolfgang, 1478-1508., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kaulbach, Friedrich August von, 1850-1920., 5 (Box 45)
    - Kaus, Max, 1891-., 2 (Box 45)
    - Kern, Anton, 1710-1747., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kerschbaumer, Anton, 1885-1931., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kesting, Edmund, 1892-1970., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kircher, Alexander, 1867-., 1 (Box 45)
    - Klein, Johann Adam, 1792-1875., 1 (Box 45)
    - Klenze, Leo von, 1784-1864., 2 (Box 45)
    - Klima, Heinz, 1924-1967., 1 (Box 45)
    - Knaus, Ludwig, 1829-1910., 1 (Box 45)
    - Knobel, George Wenzel von, 1699-1753., 1 (Box 45)
    - Koerbecke, Johann, active 1450-1490., 2 (Box 45)
    - Kolbe, Carl-Wilhelm, 1781-1835., 2 (Box 45)
    - Kolbe, Georg, 1877-1947., 2 (Box 45)
    - Kolbe, Heinrich, 1772-1836., 2 (Box 45)
    - Kolderer, Jorg, XVI Century., 1 (Box 45)
    - Konig, Johann, active 1600-1642., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kortzinger, Hugo, 1892-1967., 2 (Box 45)
    - Krafft, Johann August, 1798-1829., 1 (Box 45)
    - Krell, Hans, -1586., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kremer, Nicolaus, -1553., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kretzschmar, Bernhard, 1889-., 2 (Box 45)
    - Krodel, Matthias, -1605., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kruger, Franz, 1797-1857., 4 (Box 45)
      Artist's name also spelled "Krueger."
    - Krumpper, Hans, 1570-1634., 1 (Box 45)
    - Kunz, Emma, 1892-1963., 2 (Box 45)
    - Kupper, Will, 1893-1972., 1 (Box 45)
  - Individual Artists K., 170
    - Kersting, George, 1785-1847., 11 (Box 45)
    - Kiefer, Anselm, 1945-., 10 (Box 45)
    - Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig, 1880-1935., 77 (Box 46)
    - Klinger, Max, 1857-1920., 8 (Box 47)
    - Kobell, Wilhelm von, 1766-1885., 12 (Box 47)
    - Koch, Joseph, 1768-1839., 19 (Box 47)
    - Kollwitz, Kaethe, 1867-1945., 21 (Box 47)
    - Kulmbach, Hans von, 1476/80-1522., 12 (Box 47)
- L
  - Miscellaneous Artists L, 21 (Box 48)
    - Laib, Konrad, c.1430-1465., 3 (Box 48)
    - Lautensack, Hans Sebald, 1524-1563., 1 (Box 48)
    - Lehmann, Alfred, 1899-., 1 (Box 48)
    - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, 1881-1919., 1 (Box 48)
    - Lenk, Franz, 1898-., 2 (Box 48)
    - Lentulow, Aristarch, 1882-1943., 1 (Box 48)
    - Lessing, Karl Friedrich, 1808-1880., 3 (Box 48)
    - Levy, Rudolf, 1875-1943., 1 (Box 48)
    - Lindtmayer, Daniel, 1552-1606., 1 (Box 48)
    - Loos, Friedrich, 1797-1890., 1 (Box 48)
    - Lupertz, Markus, 1941-., 4 (Box 48)
    - Lutz, Rudolf, 1895-1966., 1 (Box 48)
    - Lux, Theodore, 1910-., 1 (Box 48)
  - Individual Artists L., 159
    - Leibl, Wilhelm, 1844-1900., 23 (Box 48)
    - Lenbach, Franz von, 1836-1904., 14 (Box 48)
    - Leu, Hans the Younger, 1490-1531., 19 (Box 49)
      - Drawings., 11 (Box 49)
      - Paintings., 8 (Box 49)
    - Liebermann, Max, 1847-1935., 47 (Box 49)
    - Liss, Johann, 1597-1629., 13 (Box 50)
    - Lochner, Stephan, 1400-1451., 43 (Box 50)
- M
  - Miscellaneous Artists M., 52 (Box 51)
    - Mack, Heinz, 1931-., 2 (Box 51)
    - Mair von Landshut, Nicolas Alexander, active 1492-1514., 4 (Box 51)
    - Maler, Hans, active 1500-1530., 3 (Box 51)
    - Marco, Karl, ?., 1 (Box 51)
    - Matare, Ewald, 1887-., 1 (Box 51)
    - Matthieu, George D., 1737-1778., 1 (Box 51)
    - Meidner, Ludwig, 1884-1966., 3 (Box 51)
    - Meister, S., 1796-1844., 1 (Box 51)
    - Meistermann, Georg, 1911-., 3 (Box 51)
    - Mengs, Ismael (?), 1688-1764., 1 (Box 51)
    - Mense, Carl, 1886-., 2 (Box 51)
    - Merian, Matthaus the Elder, 1593/5-1650/1., 1 (Box 51)
    - Merian, Matthaus the Younger, 1621-1687., 1 (Box 51)
    - Meyer, Carl Diethelm, 1840-1884., 1 (Box 51)
    - Meyer-Mengede, Heinrich, XX Century., 1 (Box 51)
    - Meyer von Bremen, Johann G., 1813-1886., 3 (Box 51)
    - Michel, Robert Johan Gustav, 1897-., 1 (Box 51)
    - Middendorf, Helmut, 1953-., 2 (Box 51)
    - Mielich, Hans, 1516-1573., 1 (Box 51)
    - Mignon, Abraham, 1640-1679., 2 (Box 51)
    - Moenkemeyer, F. W., XX Century., 1 (Box 51)
    - Moll, Oskar, 1875-1947., 1 (Box 51)
    - Moller, Anton, active 1580-1610., 1 (Box 51)
    - Morgenstern, Christian, 1805-1867., 1 (Box 51)
    - Morgenstern, J. F., 1777-1844., 1 (Box 51)
    - Morgner, Wilhelm, 1891-., 1 (Box 51)
    - Mosbrugger, Wendelin, 1760-1848., 1 (Box 51)
    - Muche, Georg, 1895-., 4 (Box 51)
    - Mueller, Albert, 1884-1963., 1 (Box 51)
    - Muller, Karl, 1818-1893., 2 (Box 51)
    - Muller-Hufschmid, Willi, XX Century., 1 (Box 51)
    - Muntz, John Henry, 1727-1798., 1 (Box 51)
    - Myten, Daniel, 1590-1658., 1 (Box 51)
  - Individual Artists M., 245
    - Macke, August, 1887-1914., 25 (Box 51)
    - Manuel, Niklaus, 1484-1530., 32 (Box 52)
      - Drawings., 14 (Box 52)
      - Paintings., 18 (Box 52)
    - Marc, Franz, 1880-1916., 40 (Box 52)